Guide to the Conklin and Rossant Reston project collection, 1960-1990
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 2: Plans, Reports and Correspondence, 1960-1987
  - Notebook of Reston Plan, 1960s (Box 15, Folder 7)
    233.10
  - Maps of Ground Plan, 1960s (Box 15, Folder 8)
    222.12
  - Reston Process of Obtaining Approval Master Plan, 1960s (Box 15, Folder 9)
    275.10
  - Credit Items, 1960s (Box 15, Folder 10)
    226.11
  - Mechanical Specifications, 1960s (Box 15, Folder 11)
    226.3
  - Housing, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    225.19
  - Reston Hold Miscellaneous, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    227.8
  - National Council of Architectural Registration Boards Application and Instructions, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    227.9
  - Correspondence: Westhampton Beach Club, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    227.11
  - Legal, Hayes, Sklar and Herzberg (including Restrictive Covenant), 1962 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    219.13
  - Reston-Master Plan, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    219.1
  - Reston-Master Plan, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Planning Miscellaneous, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    226.1
  - Specifications for First Village Center Phase 2 General Construction, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    236.1
  - Specifications for First Village Center PHase 2 General Construction, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    236.2
  - Grand Union Store Plans, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    227.4
  - Third Year Class, Pratt Institute School of Architecture, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    227.15
  - Reston, Wilbure Smith and Associates, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    233.22
  - Reston, Virginia-First Village Center Specifications Phase 1, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    235.2
  - Reston, Virginia-First Village Center Specifications Phase 2 Mechanical and Electrical, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    235.3
  - Low-Rise, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    226.22
  - Stairs, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    226.4
  - Site Work Punch List, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    227.2
  - Reston-Herman, Blum, Consulting Engineers, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Building "A", 1965 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    225.16
  - General File-Punch List ITems "Sales Buildings" and "Sales Houses", 1965 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    224.6
  - Building "E", 1965 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    226.19
  - Building "C", 1965 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    226.18
  - Building "K", 1965 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    226.17
  - Building "H", 1965 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    226.16
  - Building "B", 1965 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    226.20
  - Code, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    226.15
  - Samples: 1-Wire Mesh Screen, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    226.13
  - Proposed Physical Development Policies for Washington, D.C., 1965 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    225.10
  - Reston Industrial Center for Research and Government and the Reston Center for Industry and Government, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    225.11
  - General File-Punch List Items "Sales Buildings" and "Sales Houses", 1965 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    224.5
  - Addendum and Changes-To Plans Specifications, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    226.2
  - Commercial Spaces Punch List, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    225.17
  - Reston-Low Cost Housing (Heckscher, Simon), 1966 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    234.11
  - Office Building Punch LIst, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    225.18
  - Building "F" Punch LIst, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    225.15
  - Building "G" Punch List, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    225.13
  - Reston-Master Plan for Reston-Lecture Series, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    233.9
  - Building "D", 1966 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    226.12
  - Housing and Urban Development/Reston Housing Study, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    234.13
  - Originals for Phase Two Reports, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Part II, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    222.8
  - Transportation Grant, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    229.6
  - Reston Low Income Housing Demonstration Program Report, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    235.1
  - Reston Low Income Housing Demonstration Program Report, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Reston, Virginia, An Architectural History, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Low-Cost Housing Study-Correspondence and Minutes of Meeting, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    224.3
  - Reston, Virginia-Its Social Impact on Fairfax County, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    224.1
  - Miscellaneous about Reston, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    222.10
  - Proposal for the Comprehensive Study of Reston's Town Center, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    223.11
  - Documents on Reston, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    222.9
  - Reston Town Center Proposal, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    219.3
  - Lower Manhattan Waterfront Report, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    644.05
  - Wilkes-Encyclopedia of Architecture, 1980s (Box 20, Folder 4)
    222.11
  - Reston Anniversary Miscellaneous, 1983-1985 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    236.3
  - Reston Anniversary Minutes and Memos, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    236.5
  - Reston Community Church, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    236.8
  - Correspondence: Thesis on Goals of Robert E. Simon for Reston, 1985 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    227.10
  - Reston Miscellaneous, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    236.4
    - Sculpture: The Rest of Reston, no date; 1.
- Series 3: Publicity, 1960-1987
  Series three is entitled publicity and is dated from 1960 to 1987. The information in this series are a variety of different publicity material from Reston, such as news clippings.
  - Topic, Issue No. 65, "America's New Towns: The Human Element is the Primary Consideration", 1960s (Box 20, Folder 10)
    644.13
  - Reston-Publicity, 1960s (Box 20, Folder 11)
    228.1
  - Reston-Publicity, 1960s (Box 21, Folder 1)
    228.2
  - Reston-Publicity, 1960s (Box 21, Folder 2)
    228.3
  - Reston-Publicity, 1960s (Box 21, Folder 3)
    228.4
  - Reston-Publicity, 1960s (Box 21, Folder 4)
    228.5
  - The New York Times, Real Estate SEction (Designed by Whittlesey and Conklin), 1960s (Box 21, Folder 5)
    644.07
  - Reston-Publicity, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    228.6
  - New York Times "First Light of New Town Era is on the Horizon", 1964 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    236.7
  - The New York Times "fully Planned Town Opens in Virginia", 1965 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    644.06
  - "Lake Anne Village Center: A Planned Community Nucleus" Reprint from May Issue of Progressive Architecture, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    644.08
  - "What is the Visual Community" by Conklin, Building Research, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    644.11
  - New Towns: What Architects Should Know About Them!, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    644.10
  - Reston Publicity in Japanese, 1970s (Box 21, Folder 12)
    227.12
  - American Institute of Architects Journal, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    644.12
  - Reston Times Articles, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    227.1
  - Groupius: Rebuilding Our Communities-A Lecture on February 23, 1945, 1980s (Box 22, Folder 3)
    644.04
  - Reston-Publicity, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    226.14
  - American Architecture Now II by Barbara Diamonstein, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    644.03
  - Press/Publicity, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    236.6
- Series 4: Brochures, 1960-1975
  Series four is entitled brochures and is dated from 1960 to 1975. The brochures in this collection are mostly on utilities such as windows, fireplaces and furniture.
  - Inside Reston, Virginia (Houses, Buildings and Park descriptions), 1960s (Box 22, Folder 7)
    644.09
  - "Helmut Jacoby Architectural Presentations, 1960s (Box 22, Folder 8)
    227.14
  - Windows and Screens, 1960s (Box 22, Folder 9)
    227.6
  - Fireplaces, 1960s (Box 22, Folder 10)
    226.10
  - Furniture, 1960s (Box 22, Folder 12)
    225.2
  - Floors, 1960s (Box 22, Folder 13)
    225.1
  - Structure, 1960s (Box 22, Folder 14)
    224.10
  - Luminous Ceilings, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    225.14
  - Noise Control, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    226.8
  - Flooring, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    226.9
  - Transformers, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    226.6
  - Lumber and Plywood, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    226.5
  - Reston Industrial Center for Research and Government, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    219.4
  - "Reston Industrial Center" and Other Reston Brochures, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    227.13
  - Siding, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    225.3
  - Doors, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    225.5
  - Ceilings, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    225.6
  - Plastics, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    225.7
  - Windows, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    224.9
  - Reston, C. Hodgett's File, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    224.8
  - Booklets and Brochures, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    225.9
  - New Towns and New Communities Booklets, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    225.8
  - Reston, C. Hodgett's File (Low Cost), 1969 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    224.7
  - Heating, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    226.7
- Series 5: Images, 1960-1990
  Series five are images dated from 1960 to 1990. Some of the photographs are aerial pictures of Reston at different stages of construction.
  - Models, Aerial, of Reston (Photographs), 1960s (Box 24, Folder 1)
    223.1
    - Photograph: Architectural Model, Lake Anne Village (1503-2), ca. 1962; 1.
    - Photograph: Architectural Model, Lake Anne Village (1503-3), ca. 1962; 1.
    - Photograph: Architectural Model, Lake Anne Village (1503-5), ca. 1962; 1.
    - Photograph: Architectural Model, Lake Anne Village (1503-8), ca. 1962; 1.
  - Master Plans (Photographs), 1960s (Box 24, Folder 2)
    223.9
  - Gulf Gas Station (Photographs), 1960s (Box 24, Folder 3)
    223.8
    - Photograph: Lake Anne Village Gulf Station, Front View, no date; 1.
    - Photograph: Lake Anne Village Gulf Station, Rear View, no date; 2.
  - Variety of Homes and Buildings (Photographs), 1960s (Box 24, Folder 4)
    223.6
  - Various Sculptures and Structures (Photographs), 1960s (Box 24, Folder 5)
    223.5
  - Various Sculptures and Storefronts (Photographs), 1960s (Box 24, Folder 6)
    223.4
  - Stores around Reston (Photographs), 1960s (Box 24, Folder 7)
    223.3
  - Postcards of Reston, Virginia, 1960s (Box 24, Folder 8)
    223.2
  - Buildings in Reston (Photographs), 1960s (Box 24, Folder 9)
    644.02
  - Reston, Virginia (Slides), 1960s (Box 24, Folder 10)
    644.01
  - Reston Master Plans (Photographs), 1960s (Box 24, Folder 11)
    224.2
  - Biographical Information on William J. Conklin and Floor Plans (Photographs), 1961 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    224.4
  - Construction (Slides), 1964-1965 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    237.1
  - Construction (Slides), 1964-1965 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Construction (Slides), 1964-1965 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Aerial View of Reston, Virginia (Photographs), 1960s (Box 25, Folder 2)
    223.7
  - South Lakes Village Center (Photographs), 1990 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Series 6: Oversize, 1960-1967
  Series six is an oversize series which is dated from 1960 to 1967. The series is mostly drawing negatives for bailing designs in Reston.
  - Drawing Negatives, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    239.1
  - Drawing Negatives, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    239.2
  - Drawing Negatives, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    239.3
  - Drawing Negatives, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    239.4
  - Drawing Negatives, 1960s (Box 26, Folder 5)
    239.5
  - Negatives, 1960s (Box 26, Folder 6)
    239.6
  - Negatives, 1960s (Box 26, Folder 7)
    239.7
  - Conklin and Rossant Book with Photographs and Drawings, 1960s (Box 26, Folder 8)
    239.8